(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-25T18:22:59.950025",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
吠えるぜ
I'm gonna roar
血泥付いたって守りたい
Even covered in blood and mud, I wanna protect you
革命道中だって君に夢中
Revolution is on the way, I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
In this world soaked in darkness, I found
センティメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
甘くのめり込むんだ眼差し
That sweet, rapt gaze
変に色気あるから困った
Troubled me with its strange appeal
手を繋ぐ勇気出せなくて
Wanting to muster the courage to hold hands
身の程わきまえて出来ねえな
Knowing my place, I just can't do it
暗いトンネルの壁 滴り落ちる秘密
Walls of a dark tunnel, secrets dripping down
しおやかに高鳴る心
A heart quietly throbbing
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait...
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curses and sickness.
ここまで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild right here?
ああ うぬぼれたって
Ah, even if I'm arrogant,
逃げたって守りたい
even if I run, I want to protect you.
革命道中だって君に夢中を
Right in the middle of revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In this world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found it—
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
振り構わず側にいたい
Without caring, I want to stay by your side.
子供のようなキミにも期待しちゃうよ
I end up expecting even from a child-like you.
しがみつけば消えそうな火に
Clinging to a fire that seems to fade,
恋の爪立てて近づいて
I bare my claws of love and draw close.
身を任せ奪われて全て失ってもいい
Even if I surrender myself, get robbed, and lose everything, it's fine.
鮮やかに高鳴る心
My heart beats vibrantly.
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait...
呪いも病もキミとなら
If it's with you, curses and sickness alike—
ここまで暴れちゃってもいいかな
is it okay if I go wild right here?
ああ 泣けるぜ 全くしちゃうまで離れない
Ah, it's tear-jerking, I won't let go until it tortures me completely.
革命道中だって
Right in the middle of revolution,
君に夢中を
I'm crazy about you.
迷う旅の狭間でで見つけた
Found in the narrow gap of a bewildering journey—
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we push forward, let's do it together.
革命道中だって夢に熱中を
Right in the middle of revolution, absorbed in our dreams.
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait...
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curses and sickness.
ここまで暴れちゃってもいいよね
Is it okay if I go wild right here?
怖くたって ぬるくて
Even if it's scary, lukewarm—
尽かされたって守りたい
even if exhausted, I want to protect you.
革命道中だって君に夢中を
Right in the middle of revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In this world soaked in darkness,
見つけた
I found it—
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love.
Catch the Moment 作詞:LiSA 作曲:田淵智也
Catch the Moment / Lyrics & Music: LiSA & Tomoya Tabuchi
そっと吐き出す溜息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sighs I breathed out.
後悔は苦い味残して
Regrets left a bitter taste behind.
いつも なんで？肝心なこと言えないまま
Always, why? Without being able to say what matters most,
次の朝日が顔だしてる
the next morning sun is showing its face.
嫌になった運命をナイフで
The fate I grew sick of—
切り刻んでもう一度
I'll carve it up with a knife once more.
やり直したらキミに出会えないかも
If I redid it all, maybe I wouldn't be able to meet you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に
The moment my voice echoed,
始まる命のリミット
the limit of life begins.
心臓がカウントしてる
My heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても 終わらない願い
Even if granted, even if achieved, this wish never ends.
汗をかいて走った世界の
Running through in a sweat,
秒針はいつか止まった僕を置いていく
the world's second hand leaves behind the me that stopped.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I smile with you?
試してるんだ僕を catch the moment
It's testing me... catch the moment.
一個幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a piece of happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I grow afraid of the changing future.
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
Let's carefully nurture the seeds of affection.
分厚い雲もやがて突き破るかな
I wonder if we'll eventually break through those thick clouds.
キミの声が響いた僕の全身を通って
Your voice echoed, passing through my entire body,
心臓のドアをノックしてる
and is knocking on the door of my heart.
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ
Even being "cowardly," I can open it—
信じたいから
because I want to believe.
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に
Right at my feet where I thought there was nothing,
いつか深く確かな根を生やす
someday a deep, certain root will grow.
確かな根を生やす
Growing certain roots
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night were to come,
揺らいだりわしない
I will not waver.
何度でも追いかけたり追い越したり
Chasing and surpassing countless times,
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
You suddenly become incomprehensible,
息をしたタイミングが合うだけで
Just matching the timing of our breath
嬉しくなったりして
Makes me feel so happy.
集めた一秒を永遠にして行けるかな
Can I turn every collected second into eternity?
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
Starting the moment my voice resounds,
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting down.
叶えても叶えても 終わらない願い
Endless wishes, no matter how many come true.
叶えても叶えても
No matter how many come true,
終わらない願い
This endless wish...
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針が いつか止まった 僕を置いていく
The world's second hand, as I ran in sweat, eventually stopped and left me behind.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I smile with you?
試してるんだ僕を
It is testing me.
Catch the Moment
逃さないよ僕は この瞬間を掴め
I won't let it go, grasp this moment!
Catch the Moment
こんばんわためー！
Good evening, Watame!
お誕生日を2回迎えることになった、その名もわためぇす！
I ended up celebrating my birthday twice, aptly named Watames!
本当は6月6日が誕生日なんですけど、ごろごろが多くて中断、そして延期になり、
My birthday is actually June 6th, but due to lots of thunder, it was suspended and postponed,
今日、その名もわため生誕祭2026 アニソンナイトフィーバー2！改めて開催させていただくことになりました！
and today we are holding "Watame's Birthday Festival 2026 Anison Night Fever 2" once again!
人迅速に動いて下さった運営さんたち、そしてライブを見に来てくれている皆さん、
To the management who acted so swiftly, and everyone watching the live,
本当にありがとうございます！
thank you truly so much!
1曲目革命道中、2曲目Catch the Momentと見ていただいて分かった方もいるかもしれないんですが、
You might have realized from watching the first song "Kakumei Dōchū" and second song "Catch the Moment,"
前回のライブで放送した部分は漫画1のための録画を回してくださっていたので、そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを見ていただいて、
but the footage broadcasted in the previous live was recorded for manga 1, so you saw the crushing performance from the actual birthday on June 6th.
それ以外のソロとMCは改めてこれ以上ライブ延期にならないように、今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
For the rest of the solo and MC parts, to ensure the live wouldn't be postponed any further, we pre-recorded them this time!
なのは、未来のリアルタイムのみんなのコメントを予ッチしながらMCしたいと思いますので、いっぱいコメントしてください！
So while anticipating everyone's future real-time comments, I want to do this MC, so please leave lots of comments!
わかったよ、はーい、はーい。
Understood, yup, yup.
あ、ありがとね！おめでとうも！ありがとう！見える！見えるぞ！ふふふっ！ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you! Congrats too! Thank you! I can see! I can see them! Hehe! Thank you very much!
え、説明はここまで！ここからはいつものライブ、今日は生誕ライブなので、がたくさんこのライブに向けて
Well, that's it for the explanation! From here on, it's our usual live—today is a birthday live, so we've put a lot into preparing for this live—
準備や練習を本当にたくさんしてきました！
We really did so much preparation and practice!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you enjoy it till the end and celebrate lots!
本日のハッシュタグは、え、こちら！
Today's hashtag is, um, right here!
6月6日と変わらず、え、角巻わため生誕祭2026になりますので、たくさんのスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
Just like June 6th, it's #TsunomakiWatameBirthday2026, so please post lots of screenshots and reviews!
目指せ！またトレンド！るるるるるー！いちー！
Aim for trending again! Rururururu! One!
え、あとでじっくりねっとりに、わためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
Um, later on, thoroughly and intently, Watame wants to go check it out too, so please treat me well!
で、ここまでだんだだんの革命道中、ソードアートオンラインのCatch the Momentと歌わせていただいたんですが、
So up until now, we sang Dandadan's "Kakumei Dōchū" and Sword Art Online's "Catch the Moment,"
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を入れ込んだりしているので、みんな分かったかな？
and we incorporated staging related to the anime and original MVs, so I wonder if everyone figured it out?
ターボわためいととか分かったかな？ぜひ細かいところまで見てもらえると嬉しいです！
Did you catch Turbo Watamates and stuff? I'd be so happy if you check out the fine details!
ここからは！
From here on!
ゲストパートもあります！
There's also a guest part!
みんなの好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Maybe your favorite anime songs will come up too?
ということで、ゲストパート盛り上がっていきましょう！
With that said, let's get hyped for the guest part!
アンバランスなKissをして
Unbalanced Kiss
割れた鏡の中 映る君の姿
In the shattered mirror reflecting your figure
泣いている 泣いている
Crying, crying
細い月をなぞる指
Tracing the thin moon with my fingers
誰を呼んでいるの 消えた恋の背中
Who are you calling for, the back of vanished love
何度も何度も 君の窓を叩くから
No matter how many times, I'll knock on your window
夜の加速度に 背中押されて
Pushed by the acceleration of the night
糸が切れる様に
Like a thread about to break
ただ、君を 君を強く抱いてた
I just held you, held you tightly
アンバランスなKissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss, getting closer to love
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も 僕の心に
Your tears and sad lies sleep in my heart
眠れ
Sleep
昨日へのMerry-go-round 君を運んでゆく
Yesterday's merry-go-round carrying you away
止めたくて 止めたくて
Wanting to stop, wanting to stop
僕は鍵を探してる
I'm searching for the key
崩れ落ちそうな 空を支えて ひとり立ち尽くす
Supporting the crumbling sky, standing alone
ただ、君の 君の側に いいたいよ
I just want to be by your side, stay by your side
アンバランスなKissで書かれた ふたりのシナリオ
The scenario of the two drawn with an unbalanced kiss
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても 君のすべてが 痛い
Even if not as strong as love, all of you is painful
痛い
Painful
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be by your side
いたいよ
I want to be with you
アンバランスなKissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss, getting closer to love
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も 僕の心に
Your tears and sad lies sleep in my heart
眠れ 君の心が僕を呼ぶまで 抱きしめあえる 日まで
Until the day our hearts call out and embrace each other
長い髪なびかせて 悩ましげなボディ
Floating your long hair with a bewitching body
この都会をハイヒールで 飛び回れば Big money coming, yeah!
If I jump around this city in high heels, big money coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下 時代錯誤の罠
At the foot of the skyscrapers, a trap of anachronism
血迷った 危ない奴らなら 極楽へいかせちゃうわ
If you're dangerous guys who have lost your way, I'll send you to paradise
大胆な私の業の中でれでも
Out of all the bold techniques I have
スキなのをあげる
The one you like...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out.
行き場のない あなたGhostだから…
Because you're a ghost with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out.
私が今 見つけ出して…
I'm finding you right now...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印もいいけれど神神通機はどう?
Vacuuming is fine, but how about a spiritual staff?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't tolerate any selfishness.
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I won't let you escape, big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから ゴージャスなライフも
From a conscious dress to a gorgeous life,
それが私のスタイル
That's always my style.
クールだと誰かがいうけれど 必ず
Someone might call it cool, but I will definitely...
幸せをあげる
...bring you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out 行き場のない あなたGhostだから…
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out, because you're a ghost with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out 私が今 見つけ出して…
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out, I'm finding you right now...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out 行き場のない あなたGhostだから…
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out, because you're a ghost with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out 私が今 見つけ出して…
Bye-bye, sadness, and find out, I'm finding you right now...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"Just stay broken like that,"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
discarding it, running away—
強くないよ
I'm not strong enough.
ほら もう一度 心臓高鳴る
Look, once again my heartbeat echoes.
何が正しいかなんて わからないけど
I don't know what is right, but...
形のないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Only formless things become precious to us.
飾らない言葉だけが 強く結ばれてる
Only unadorned words are bound together strongly.
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling again, tumbling over, yet still unbreakable—
魂の色は 何色ですか
what color is the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, putting up a strong front, yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I am confirming the shape of my soul.
深い地底の底で一人 扉と鍵を探す
Deep in the bottom of the earth, alone, I search for a door and a key.
おとぎ話は ほら 泡の様に全部消えて
The fairy tale, look, vanishes entirely like bubbles.
葛藤 残像だけ 次のページへ
Tendrils and afterimages lead to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
Growing branches split apart, and each goes their own way.
寂しい想い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are strongly taking root.
まだ貫いて失くして それでも挫けない
Still piercing through, losing things, yet not breaking,
心はどこに 器はどこに
where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ零されて落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just spilling and falling, yet I still want to convey it,
魂の日々を 魂の意志を ずっと
the days of the soul, the will of the soul, forever.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of the soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of the soul?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In a transparent past, in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
what color are you, living?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling again, yet not shattering,
魂の色は 何色ですか
what color is the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, yet I still want to find it,
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
confirming the shape of the soul,
ずっと...
forever...
耶！三曲連続でお届けしましたが、
Yay! I just performed three songs in a row.
みんな楽しんでますか？快適に見れてますか？
Did everyone enjoy it? Are you watching comfortably?
Ｙａ-Ｙｕ-Ｙｕ白書のアンバランスなキスをしては月をね映してもらったり、
In "YuYu Hakusho's" "Unbalanced Kiss", we had the moon reflected,
戦闘心をイメージして炎に囲まれていたり、
and we were surrounded by flames to evoke fighting spirit.
ダンスの振りにもねキャラクターの技が入ったりしていたりしまして、
The dance choreography also incorporated character moves and techniques,
ゴーストスイーパー美神のゴーストスイーパーにも
like holding paper charms in "Ghost Sweeper Mikami",
お札をね持っている振りがあったり、 あとは幽霊が飛んでいるそんな演出があったりしました！
or having ghosts flying around in the background!
気づいたかな？
Did you notice?
そして、ソードアート・オンラインのアニマは
Also, "ANIMA" from "Sword Art Online"
いつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で、
is a song I've always wanted to sing someday,
念願の日の出たんですが、いかがだったでしょうか？
so I finally got my wish, how was it?
いやーかっこよかったな！すごいな！
Man, it was so cool! Amazing!
わためバキバキだな！笑
Watame is ripped! Haha.
でも、まだこれで終わりではありません！
But this isn't the end yet!
ここからは鏡ゲートを使ったギミックや...
From here on, we'll use mirror gates and gimmicks...
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Stirring up the media with an invincible smile,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
that mysterious secret you want to know.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her clumsy side is part of her territory.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, so perfect and deceitful,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol!
今日何食べた？ 好きな本は？
What did you eat today? What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything.
それは内緒
That's a secret.
何を言われてものらりくらり
No matter what you're asked, you evasively glide past.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So calmly, yet so brilliantly,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
the secret that seems visible yet isn't is the taste of honey.
あれもないないない
There's none, none, none of that.
これもないないない
There's none, none, none of this either.
好きなタイプは？相手は？さあ答えて
What's your type? Who's your partner? Come on, answer!
誰かが好きになることなんて私わからなくてさ
I don't even know what it means to love someone...
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Couldn't beat her smile, it stirred up all the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Secret side, I wanna know it, so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even that elusive side, part of her controlled area
完璧で究極のアイドル
Complete and perfect, ultimate idol
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
Whenever you go out for fun, tell me, where do you go?
何も食べてない　それは秘密なの
Haven't eaten anything, it's a secret, unknown
何も言ってない　なんて言わせない
Any questions you're facing, always acting so vaguely
秘密の蜜の味
So unconcerned, although you brightly glow
あれもこれもそれも何？
Any seemingly unveiled secrets are as sweet as honey
好きなタイプは？相手はいるの？さあ答えて
What's your type of guy? Any partner? Now, answer this!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
"I don't have any idea how I could love anyone"
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Cannot find out if it's true or it's a lie
そんな言葉にまた一人陥る
Once again, there's somebody who's fallen for the words and cues
また人を陥落した
Made him lose his head over you
誰もが目を奪われていく
That emotion melts all hearts, all eyes on you
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
'Cause you are perfect, the most ultimate idol
金輪際現れない
Unrivalled, will not appear again
一番星の生まれ変わりだ
It's the brightest star reborn, yes, indeed
その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, using that smiling face, that "I love you" again
誰も彼も虜にしていく
Now, everybody is lured and captivated by you
その瞳がその言葉が
The pupil that you got, the words you vocalize
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
Even when untrue, it's your perfected ai
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, we all know she's very special, yes
我々は端からおまけです
We had lost the fight before it started, so impressed
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Miss, I'm such a star, serving as support to her grace
全てがあの子のおかげなわけない
Cannot tell me everything was because of her
しゃらくさい
No, it's not right, out of line
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How can we not feel jealous while being around
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
It's not a joke, you know, right? So, I cannot forgive you for that
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
Completely deny, imperfect you that I sight
自分を許せない
Myself, no pardon allowed
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't allow anyone if it's not you, strongest of all
誰もが信じ崇めてる
That emotion seized all hearts worshiping you, yes, indeed
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
So strong, it's you, unrivaled idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
There cannot be weaknesses to find
一番星を宿している
The brightest star is residing in you
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
The gaps and shortcomings, don't show 'em, dammit, dammit
知りたくないところは見せずに
Parts nobody wants to know should remain hidden
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
One and only, if it's different, no way, no way
それこそ本物のアイ
Such a true love, it's the realest ai
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Showing this smile, my own weapon boiling media
隠し切るこの秘密だけは
Keeping everything about my secret deep inside
「愛してる」って嘘で積むキャリア
"I'm in love with you," my career is built on such a lie
これこそ私なりの愛だ
It's the way I know to show my love, without a doubt
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Running down, my sweat is flowing, cleanest aqua, right?
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Ruby hidden under my eyelids where it resides
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
I sing and dance around, look at me, I'm maria
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
So, lying surely is the greatest kind of love
誰かに愛されたことも
I recall no one that loved me whole before
誰かのこと愛したこともない
And I've not been in love with anybody before
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
Now, the lies I'm making up, I'm hoping that a day comes when they all become true
信じてる　いつかきっと全部手に入れる
I'm believing it, one day, I will hold everything that I pursue
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Yes, I am so greedy, true voracious idol
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
So, sincerely, what I'm wishing for is to love each of you with all my heart
今日も嘘をつくの
And so, today, I lie again
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
The words I vocalize inside of me, I'm wishing that one day they come true
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Up to this day, I've not been able to let you...
あ、やっと言えた
And you hear me saying those meaningful words
これは絶対嘘じゃない
I, I said it at last, I know it's not a lie as I'm voicing these words
愛してる
I love you
あいうえ お菓子した かきくけ こんなにも
Ai, ue, okashi, shita, kaki kuu kke? Konna ni mo
さしすせ ソフトクリーム 五臓六腑でいこう
Sashi su se sofuto kuriimu, gozou roppu de ikou
タッチついて トルテ来た 何？ヌネのり塩
Tacchi tsuite torute kita, nani? Nune nori shio
はっ！ヒフヘホットパイと みんなでぬくぬく
Ha-! Hifu hehotto pai to, minna de nukunuku
ショートケーキ ふわり キャンディー ぺろぺろ
Shooto keeki fuwari, kyandii pero pero
チョコレートの川で 綿菓子雲見た
Chokoreeto no kawa de, watagashi kumo mita
アイスクリームと プリンのお城で
Aisu kuriimu to, purin no oshiro de
カスタード渡狸 二人のランデブー
Kasutaado watanuki, futari no randebuu
パフェ色サンデー あんこもハッピー
Pafe iro sandee, anko mo happii
タイ焼きにクリーム 小悪魔ドロップ
Taiyaki ni kuriimu, koakuma doroppu
カップケーキから 苺あんみつまで
Kappu keeki kara, ichigo anmitsu made
国境なきsweets 仲良くなれるよ
Koukyou naki sweets, nakayoku nareru yo
ぼんやり夢見てごらん キャラメルみたいにくっつこう
Bonyari yume mite goran, kyarameru mitai ni kuttsukou
まみむめもモンブラン やい！故ヨーグルト
Ma mi mu me mo mon buran, yai! Yue yooguruto
ラリルレロロールケーキ 渡狸とKissを
Rari ru ure rooru keeki, watanuki to kiss wo
あいうえ お菓子した かきくけ こんなにも
Ai, ue, okashi, shita, kaki kuu kke? Konna ni mo
さしすせ ソフトクリーム 五臓六腑でいこう
Sashi su se sofuto kuriimu, gozou roppu de ikou
のんびり早弁 焼きのりあぶって
Nonbiri haya ben, yaki nori abutte
おにぎりコロコロ 友達ほかほか
Onigiri koro koro, tomodachi hoka hoka
紅葉まんじゅうと あんぱんお月さま
Momiji manjuu to, anpan otsuki sama
渡狸に始まり 渡狸に終わる日々
Watanuki ni hajimari, watanuki ni owaru hibi
ほんのり見つめてごらん 甘くて苦い夕焼けを
Honnori mitsumete goran, amakute nigai yuuyake wo
タッチついて トルテ来た 何？ヌネのり塩
Tacchi tsuite torute kita, nani? Nune nori shio
はっ！ヒフヘホットパイと みんなでぬくぬく
Ha-! Hifu hehotto pai to, minna de nukunuku
まみむめもモンブラン やい！故ヨーグルト
Ma mi mu me mo mon buran, yai! Yue yooguruto
ラリルレロロールケーキ 渡狸とKissを
Rari ru ure rooru keeki, watanuki to kiss wo
あいうえ お菓子した かきくけ こんなにも
Ai, ue, okashi, shita, kaki kuu kke? Konna ni mo
さしすせ ソフトクリーム 五臓六腑でいこう
Sashi su se sofuto kuriimu, gozou roppu de ikou
タッチついて トルテ来た 何？ヌネのり塩
Tacchi tsuite torute kita, nani? Nune nori shio
はっ！ヒフヘホットパイと ふたりでぬくぬく
Ha-! Hifu hehotto pai to, futari de nukunuku
まみむめもモンブラン やい！故ヨーグルト
Ma mi mu me mo mon buran, yai! Yue yooguruto
ラリルレロロールケーキ 渡狸とKissを
Rari ru ure rooru keeki, watanuki to kiss wo
渡狸の甘みと 渡狸の苦み
Watanuki no amami to, watanuki no nigami
渡狸の酸味で すきすきラブ・コンボ
Watanuki no sanmi de, suki suki rabu konbo
ミルフィーユワッフルボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bon-bon
ムース渡狸パイ
Mousse, Watanuki, pie
シュークリームバナナゼリー
Cream puff, banana jelly
ババロア渡狸
Bavarois, Watanuki
ホットケーキバアムクーヘン
Pancakes, Baumkuchen
渡狸渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki
バター渡狸クレープ
Butter Watanuki crepe
渡狸渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki
渡狸とごはん
Meals with Watanuki
渡狸とおやつ
Snacks with Watanuki
渡狸と肉まん
Meat buns with Watanuki
渡狸と北京ダック
Peking duck with Watanuki
みつまめ渡狸
Mitsumame Watanuki
渡狸シロップ
Syrup Watanuki
金時渡狸
Kintoki Watanuki
大盛り渡狸丼
Bowl of Watanuki rice extra
こんがり思い出色
Well-made in the color of memories
ハチミツみたいにとろける
Melting like honey
あいうえお菓子した
Love at the top, candy at the bottom
柿食うけ?こんなにも
Eat a persimmon? There's so much to do
さしすせソフトクリーム
Let's take a soft-serve ice cream
五臓六腑で行こう
and live life to the fullest
タッチついてトルテ来た
After a touch, a torte arrives,
何?ヌデのり塩
what? With salt on top
はっ!ヒフヘホットパイとふたりでぬくぬく
Oh! Hot pie with just us two while we cuddle
まみむめモンブラン やい!ヨーグルト
Mont Blanc, yay! Yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ 渡狸とkissを
A roll cake and a kiss from Watanuki
渡狸の甘みと 渡狸の苦みと
With the sweetness and bitterness of Watanuki
渡狸の酸味と 好き好きラブ・コンボ
and acidity, we make a love combo
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
うー！がー！
Roar!
高らかに笑い笑えばフレレンズ
Laugh together and be friends, friends
喧嘩して すちくみちくしても仲良し
Even if we fight, we are best friends
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
There are animals, but no pariahs
本当の愛はここにある
The true love was here
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Here, let's go on an adventure with you
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だだから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has a unique shape, attracting us
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun,
はじめまして
nice to meet you,
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
うー！がー！
Roar!
振り返れば あちらこちらでトラブル
Look back and everywhere I see troubles
なんてこった
What the heck,
てんでバラバラ ちんぷんかんぷんまとまらない
scattered and completely unsettled
けものですもの 大目に見ててね
We are animals, so please forgive us
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely
そう 君も飾らなくて大丈夫
Yes, you don't have to maintain your image
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you in the Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
I'm so glad to meet you today
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
Smiling tenderly anytime, anywhere for you
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
Gate that is open, after talking of dreams,
どこまでも
anywhere
続いてくグレートジャーニー
the great journey continues
Oh 東へ吠えろ 西へ吠えろ
Oh, roar to east, roar to west
世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Sound the safari melody all over the world
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has a unique shape, attracting us
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun,
はじめまして
nice to meet you,
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
うー！がー！
Roar!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 素敵な旅立ち
Dreamy departure
ようこそ ジャパリパーク！
Welcome to the Japari Park!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has a unique shape, attracting us
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun,
はじめまして
nice to meet you,
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you
うー！がー！
Roar!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ ララララ 素敵な旅立ち
Dreamy departure
ようこそ ジャパリパーク！
Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララララ
La la la la la la la la
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful journey
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
Oh oh...
Night of fire
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door I'll open
Speak my name now, speak if it you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
you've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me, come over over the top
you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
you've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me, come over over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the fire of the night
Come on baby, let it go
Come on baby, let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door I'll open
Speak my name now, speak if it you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
you've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me, come over over the top
you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
you've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me, come over over the top
You'll have a night of fire
You better better stay
The prayer to play
Come over over me
You've never been here
Night of fire
You've better better begin
Come over over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco night
Night of fire
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now
Speak it if you know how fly to me
Get ready for the night of fire
You've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come over, over me
Come over, over the top
You'll have a night of fire
ていうことで、ここまでたくさんの一番
So, up until this point,
本当たくさんのゲストさんたちと歌って踊ってきたんですが
we've sung and danced with so many—
いかがだったでしょうか?
truly many guest performers!
楽しんでますか?
Are you enjoying yourselves?
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが
It's pretty rare to have this many holomen
集まることってないので、
gather all in one place,
もう本当、生誕祭大祭りって感じで嬉しいです!
so I'm just overjoyed!
ゲストさんたちにも大きな拍手を!
Let's give a huge round of applause to the guests!
やった、ありがとうみんな!
Yay, thank you everyone!
ゲストのみんなありがとう!
Thank you to all the guests!
このね、鏡のモニターから登場するという演出をやってみたいなと思って
I wanted to try an entrance using the mirror monitors,
アイドルとスイーツパレードで実現していただきました!
and we brought it to life with idols and sweets parade!
あの、わためいと、スコブさん、エルフさん、ざゆさんたちがペンライトをね、振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし、
It was so cute how Watame, Scobo, Elf-san, and Zui-san all waved penlights for me,
やっぱりホロメンって可愛いよね!
and holomen are just so cute, aren't they?
あと、よーこそジャパリパークでは、
And speaking of Japan Relief Park,
サバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて、
it's surrounded by carnivorous animals in the savanna,
みんなが仲良くなっていく様子を表現させていただきました。
making everyone grow closer together.
まあ、ちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怖かったけどね。
Well, everyone's expressions were a bit scary at the end, though!
そして、「Night of Fire」!
And then there was "Night of Fire."
これはもう、英語の上手なIDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って、
I wanted to sing it alongside all the English ID members,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように英語頑張ったんだけど、
so I practiced hard so I wouldn't stand out awkwardly standing next to them.
大丈夫だったかな?
Did I do okay?
海外にっきー!
Overseas Nikki—
英語上手? 英語上手?
"Your English is great! Your English is great!"
ってコメントが来てると思う。
I'm sure I'm getting those comments.
ありがとうございます!
Thank you!
でね、もっと気になるところがあったかなと思うんですが、
But, you know, there's one more thing you might be curious about.
あ、車ね? せめてかね。
The car, at least!
あとはパラパラ踊るギリワルロボね? やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです!
And I also got to dance as much as I wanted to Giri Giri Robo, so I had so much fun!
でも、まだ終わりじゃない!
But it's not over yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててください!
I'm going to go change, so please wait for me!
あ、もう着替え終わった。
Ah, my change is done.
で、さて、
Now,
次の曲なんですが、なんと、なんかみんなもう知ってそうだけど、
for the next song—I'm sure many of you already know,
次の曲は新曲、「灰色の証明」をやります!
the next song is my brand-new single, "Haiiro no Shoumei"!
わためチャンネルにてMV公開中なので、MVもぜひ見てください!
It's currently premiering on Watame's channel, so please check out the MV!
そして、楽曲リリースもしているので、いいなと思ったらぜひ買って下さい!
The single is also available for release, so if you like it, please buy it!
よろしくお願いします!
I'm counting on you!
では、新曲「灰色の証明」魂を込めて歌います。
Now, I will sing my new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei," putting my whole soul into it.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
静寂に包まれた ゼロ地点の感情で
Wrapped in silence, in zero-point emotions,
期待を背負っているのは私ではないから
carrying expectations that aren't even mine—
主人公はいつだって“輝いている誰か”で
The protagonist is always just "someone who is shining."
見上げるだけじゃ何も変わらない
Just looking up to them changes nothing at all.
今この時だけの 瞬間的な優位性で駆け抜けて
Dash through with a fleeting superiority unique to this moment,
灰色の空裂いて
splitting the gray sky.
“私”の全てを“運命の物語(シナリオ)”に叩きつけて打ち砕け
Pounding and smashing "my" all into the "scenario of destiny"—
自信は微塵もない あるのは渇望だけ
I have not an ounce of confidence, only yearnings.
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I'll just prove my own life,
“此処”にいた事を刻むように
as if carving the fact that I was right here.
綺麗な勝ち方は
Winning gracefully
望むべくもない
is out of the question,
華やかさも必要ない
and flashiness isn't needed either.
それが私だから
Because that's who I am.
歴史はいつだって勝者が作るモノ
History is always written by the victors,
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
but memory isn't bound by that.
今この時だけは決断的な刹那性に飛び込んでけ
Right now, in this moment, dive into decisive ephemerality!
灰色なしで描く“私”の思いが
The feelings of "me" painted without gray
美しき痛みをも乗り越えてかき換えてく
surpass even the beautiful pain and rewrite it.
後悔は1ミリもないあるのは灼熱だけ
There is not a millimeter of regret, only burning heat.
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
As if kicking up my own life.
始まりは些細 最早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial; it doesn't matter anymore.
突き動かされた指先を伸ばす
I extend my driven fingertips.
現実とは残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I don't realize reality is cruel,
諦めるその時は今ではなかったらしい
it seems the time to give up wasn't now.
灰色の空描くもう一度点火して
Paint the gray sky, ignite once more,
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
just to prove my own life
そこにいた事を刻むように
as if carving the fact that I was there.
はーい！
Hi!
ってことで、新曲『灰色の証明』
So, my new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei,"
やっと！披露できた！やっと初披露できた！
was finally performed! Finally performed for the first time!
聞いてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は岸田教団&THE明星ロケッツのみなさんに制作していただきまして、
This song was produced by Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets,
スポーツだったりみんなが頑張りたい時に力になれるような応援ソングを作りたいと思い色々語ったらかなり熱くてかっこいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
and when I talked about wanting to make an uplifting song for sports or when everyone wants to do their best, it turned out to be a really passionate and cool track!
うまくいかないことがあってもまた立ち上がって前に進む私にとっても背中を押してくれるそんな特別な楽曲になりました！
Even when things don't go well, standing back up and moving forward—it became such a special song that pushes my back too!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if it's the same for all of you.
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て、楽曲もぜひ購入して、わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you watch the new music video a lot, purchase the song, and support Watame's music!
目指せ3rdライブ！
Aim for the 3rd live!
と…あ、
And... oh,
ここでまだ告知していないものが一つありまして！ライブじゃないんですけど、
there's one thing I haven't announced yet! It's not a live concert, but...
なんと！だーーーん！
guess what! Ta-da!
角巻わためのHave a nice day書籍化決定！
Tsunomaki Watame's "Have a nice day" book publication is decided!
ということで、はばないが本になります！
So, "Habani" is becoming a book!
出版社は『かいけつゾロリ』や『おしりたんてい』
Published by Poplar Publishing, famous for works like
などで有名なポプラ社様より、
"Kaiketsu Zorori" and "Oshiri Tantei,"
オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
it's scheduled for release in December with original goods!
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待っててもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a bit far off, but I'd be happy if you look forward to it!
そして、どどん！
And, ta-da!
今年も角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
This year's Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Commemorative Goods are now available for order!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてください！
Let me introduce the lineup once again!
どどどどどん！
Ba-ba-ba-ba-bam!
ふみママ描き下ろしのみんなのあったかブランケット、なんとセクシーです！
Fumi-mama's newly drawn "Everyone's Warm Blanket"—it's so sexy!
そして、裏面にはわためいとがいます！丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますのでツーウェイでも使えます！
And on the back, there's a Watamate! When you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate, so you can use it two ways!
ぜひぬくもりを感じてください！
Please feel the warmth!
そして、どどどどどん！
And, ba-ba-ba-ba-bam!
わため＆わためいと温感マグカップ！
Watame & Watamate Thermal Mug Cup!
こちらはモタ先生に描き下ろししていただきまして、最初は夜の風景なんですけど、あったかいものを入れていただくとその熱を感じて朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
This was newly drawn by Mota-sensei. At first it's a night scene, but when you pour something warm in, it senses the heat and the design changes to a morning scenery!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので、配信を見ながらぜひあったかい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
It was designed with my streams in mind, so please enjoy a warm drink while watching the stream!
そして、え、まだあります！
And there's more!
どどどどどどどどどん！
Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-bam!
え、わためいとクッション！
Um, Watamate Cushion!
クッションとして使うもよし、飾るもよし、とっても可愛いクッションなのでぜひお部屋に...
You can use it as a cushion or display it—it's such a cute cushion, so please put it in your room...
おいてみてください！
Please try placing it!
最後に、だんだんだんだん...だんだん！
And finally, slowly... slowly... slowly!
「わためなりきりアイマスク」！
The "Watame Cosplay Eye Mask"!
眠っている顔と、わためといえばこれ！な表情にしていただきました！
We had it made with a sleeping face, and... Watame's signature expression!
果たして需要があるのか、気になる方はぜひなりきりアイマスクを手にいれてください！
Wondering if there's demand for it? Be sure to get your Watame Cosplay Eye Mask!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入いただいた方には...だんだんだんだん...だんだん！
Those who purchase these goods as a full set will receive... slowly... slowly... slowly!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、角巻わためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
As a bonus: a postcard with Watame's signature and message, and 15 short voice clips!
今年も無制限で直筆をね、書かせていただく予定なので、ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
This year, I plan to write each one by hand without limit, so definitely take this chance to get yours!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！楽曲リリース中！誕生日グッズ発売中！
With that said, the new song MV is out now, the song is released, and birthday goods are on sale!
12月ハードカバー書籍刊行決定ーー！
A December hardcover book release has been decided!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you for your support!
このあとは、10時15分からメンゲンアンコールライブもありますので、
After this, starting at 10:15 PM, there's also a members-only encore live,
よかったらメンゲン、あ、間違えた。メンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
so if you'd like—ah, my bad—join as a member and let's keep enjoying it together!
今年はなんと2Days！お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれてありがとう！
This year is a 2-day event! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！
I was so happy!
それではメンゲンアンコールライブでお会いしましょう！
Well then, let's meet at the members-only encore live!
またねーー！
See you later!
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!
静寂に包まれたゼロ地点の感情で
Surrounded by silence, with zero-point emotions,
期待を背負っているのは私ではないから
I'm not the one carrying expectations, because
主人公はいつだって「輝いている誰か」で
The protagonist is always "someone who shines",
見上げるだけじゃ何も変わらない
Just looking up won't change anything at all.
今この時だけの瞬間的な優位性で駆け抜けて
Racing ahead with a momentary advantage unique to this very moment,
灰色の大空裂いて「私」の全てを
Tearing through the gray sky, hammering all of "me"
「運命の物語(シナリオ)」に叩きつけて打ち砕き
Into the "story of destiny" and smashing it to pieces.
自信は微塵もないあるのは渇望だけ
I don't have an ounce of confidence, all I have is yearning,
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
Just to prove my own life,
「此処」にいた事を刻むように
As if engraving the fact that I was "here".
(even if you're feeling unsure)
(so you won't have any regrets)
(i'll keep chasing it forever)
(that passion creates what is right)